About Dataset
(fotoğraf)

The dataset contains 2 folders: one with the test data and the other one with train data.

The test-train split ratio is ??, with the test dataset containing ?? images and the train dataset containing ??.

The images have a resolution of ?? x ?? pixels in RGB color model.
Both the folders contain 6 main classes and 54 sub classes(It contains every number, color and okeys on the tile.):



Inspiration
As a result of our deep research on the internet, we realized that there is no data set belonging to Okey (Rummikub). That's why we decided to make one.

This data set was prepared by @erogluegemen and @zeynepcaglabaykan for the 101 Okey project.

You can use this data set in Okey(Rummikub) projects where you will use image processing.

Remember to upvote if you found the dataset useful :3.




Collection Methodology
The data set was tried to be obtained by downloading images from Google Images and Bing Images, but there are no images of these tiles. That's why we decided to shoot it ourselves :').

Initially, 10 pictures were taken for each numerical value of each color set.
Then, augmentation process was applied to each of these pictures.
100 augmented images were produced for each tile (200 for okeys).

The images with a .HEIC format were transformed into .jpg images. 

The obtained images were (randomly shuffled and resized)?? so that all the images had a resolution of (240x240)?? pixels.

Then, they were split into train and test datasets and saved.

# Tags
(computer science) (image data) (computer vision) (game) (image processing)
